PORFIRIO BASALDUA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Software engineer with more than 4 years of experience with all the phases of the SDLC, including leadership experience as team leader. An avid desire for learning combined with flexibility and collaboration skills such as team building make him well suited to tackle complex problems in fast-changing environments.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: (+52) 55 65 08 37 22 Email: porfirioBasaldua@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/basporfirio

CERTIFICATIONS

January 2022. Scrum Alliance Certified Scrum Master (CSM). December 2021. Professional Cloud Architect - Google Cloud Platform

SKILLS

Soft skills

- Active listening.
- Effective communication.
- Leadership.
- Coaching.
- Teamwork.
- Creativity.
- Honesty.

Programming and tools

- Python (Advanced).
- Flask (Advanced)
- REST APIs (Advanced)
- SQL (Advanced).
- Javascript (Intermediate).
- React (Intermediate).
- Architecting in the cloud (Intermediate).
- AWS (Beginner).
- HTML5 (Intermediate).
- Bootstrap (Intermediate).
- CSS (Intermediate)

Languages

- English (Advanced).
- Spanish (Native).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical team lead

Vexi

January 2021 - present

- Managed a virtual team of 7 engineers distributed across 3 states, maintaining an average 94% satisfaction score.
- Served as a point of contact for external stakeholders and other team leaders, sharing project advancements as well as coordinating dependencies.
- Recruited and trained 3 engineers who still contribute to the enterprise.
- Coordinated projects that involved up to 25 people, including senior stakeholders, business experts and other engineers.
- Recommended a team member for promotion, resulting in one new team formed within the organization.
- Designed architectural structure of the products that the team developed and maintained.
- Spearheaded the adoption of React as a framework for development, which resulted in a 40% decrease in time to build new software.
- Collaborated with junior developers to solve challenging technical issues.

Relevant projects:

- Renovate the in-house ERP.
- Develop new system for the Collections department.
- Redesign credit card management app.
- Update entire back-end from Python version from 2.7 to Python 3.8.
- Lift-and-shift workloads to the cloud.

Full Stack developer

Vexi

February 2018 - December 2020

- Gathered, analyzed and helped implement requirements for web applications, working with technologies across the technology stack.
- Applied complex algorithms, including parallelism and recursion to solve business problems.
- Introduced SQL queries and reports that allowed business managers to monitor key metrics for their processes.
- Improved code quality by writing unit tests for new and existing code.

Relevant projects:

- Create connection to AMEX network
- Overhauled Accounting system
- Create in-house ERP

EDUCATION

Monterrey Institute of Technology and Higher Education

Bachelor of Science in Robotics and Digital Systems, August 2012 - December 2016

- Graduated with honors.
- Score of 90, out of 100.
- Volunteer for student association.